Sameer Kumar

+91 8733977513 | sameervirak@gmail.com | Ahmedabad, India, 380015 www.linkedin.com/in/sameer-kumar

SUMMARY

Junior Front End Developer with experience at Zealous System, skilled in Angular 17+, TypeScript, and .NET Core Web API. Successfully optimized performance for an Al-driven platform, enhancing user experience. A collaborative team player with a passion for creating responsive applications and a knack for troubleshooting complex issues.

SKILLS

Angular 17+ and HTML/CSS
JavaScript and TypeScript

. NET Core Web API Bootstrap framework

EXPERIENCE

Angular Developer Intern, Scikey Surat India

Desember 2022-April 2023

- Developed responsive web applications using the Angular framework and TypeScript.
- Utilized RxJS library for reactive programming within the application.

Junior Front End Developer, Zealous System Ahmedabad, India

Jul 2023 - Current

- Developed UI with Angular 17, TypeScript, and RxJS. Collaborated with designers and backend developers.
- Optimised performance for an Al-powered real estate financing platform called Zavvie.
- Collaborated with design teams for seamless integration of user interfaces into scalable applications.
- Implemented RESTful APIs to enhance application functionality and user experience.
- Troubleshot and resolved front-end issues reported by users or QA teams.
- · Participated in daily standup meetings with team members to discuss progress and challenges faced.
- · Participated in sprint planning meetings to discuss upcoming tasks and deadlines.

EDUCATION

B.Tech, Computer Science

Parul University Vadodara, India, Apr 2023

Portfolio & Profile

www.linkedin.com/in/sameer-kumar https://samkr8639.github.io/My-website/

Project

Zavvie (Oct 2023–Present) — Built and maintained user interfaces with Angular 17, TypeScript, and RxJS. Worked closely with designers and backend developers and improved application performance for an Al-powered real estate financing platform.